Now I'm ready to make the backing of our picture frame.
We're going to be using a second piece of cardboard, of carton, for this.
The way I get the size of the backing is I measure the space in the picture frame, the hole that's in the middle that I've cut for the picture, and I increase the size by a quarter of an inch.
So whatever the size is I add a quarter of an inch around the entire border: first on the left side and the right side, then I measure the top and the bottom.
And I also add a quarter of an inch whatever the size is.
And once I have those measurements I go and take my second piece of cardboard and make my points using the same measurements that I just took from the inside of the picture frame.
And I make a line.
So once I've drawn my lines and I have the outline of the back that I want to use for the picture frame I can go ahead and start cutting it down to size.
Of course when making the image of your picture frame, the actual drawing, you have to make sure that you leave this quarter of an inch around all sides of the picture without getting too close to the end of the picture frame.
Because you're going to need that extra space so that it hangs over and actually covers the picture from the back.
So make sure you left enough room around the edges, the outer edges, of your picture frame. So now once I've drawn the outlines on the back of the picture frame I go ahead and cut around the edges being left with a square piece of cardboard that's going to sit right onto the back of the picture and make up the backing of the picture frame.
We see now that the backing that we've cut fits right over the picture frame and we've left enough border so that it doesn't fall through and it also doesn't show over the edges of the picture frame.
And now we go ahead and place the picture in between both pieces of cardboard and cover it with the plastic and we'll have a nice seal for our picture frame.
So now I've shown you how to make a backing for the picture frame.